Guide to the Togo Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Togo collection
1956-2007
MS 1546
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Togo.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Subsequent accessions may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Togo.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Togo -- Description and travel; Togo -- Economic conditions; Togo -- Politics and government; Togo -- Social conditions
- Inventory, 1961-1992
  - Olympio, Sylvanus: presidential address, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Réalité Togolaise, "Les 4 Piliers de la Vitalité Togolaise", 1965 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General/tourist information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Le Combat": Organe du Mouvement Togolais pour la Démocratie (MTD), 1982 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Togo Bulletin," David Apter and Associates for Togo Information Service, 1982. 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "L'Eveil du Travailleur Togolaise - (ETRATO)": Organe de la Confederation Nationale des Travailleurs de Togo (CNTT), 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agbetra, Aissah, Ministre de la Santé Publique, des Affaires Sociales, et de la Condition Feminine du Togo: declaration d'acceptation, 1989 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CAR: communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, 1991 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Association de Défense des Togolais Oubliés et Laissés pour Compte (DETOL): communication à la Conférence Nationale du Togo, 1991 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Déclaration de Politique Générale"; la Convention Démocratique des Peuples Africains: communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, 1991 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Introduction au Débat Économique," Union pour la Démocratie et la Solidarité (UDS): communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Organisation des Travailleurs du Togo pour la Démocratie (OTTD): communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, 1991 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - L'Ordre des Avocats: communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cercle des Jeunes Filles Democrates (C.J.F.D.): communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Monde Rural Oti," présenté par Darago Quattara Dréf à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Olympio, Gilchrist: intervention devant la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Union Togolaise pour la Démocratie (UTD): communication à la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Codjie, Marcel, victime et rescape du Camp Rouge de Kazaboua: témoignage pour la Conférence Nationale Souveraine, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newspapers, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Additional Material, 1978, 1993; Accession 1996-M-064
  - Additional printed materials, 1978, 1993 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1956-1992; Accession 2000-M-038
  - Ambassade de France, Service de Presse et d'Information [African Affairs No. 16A and Speeches and Press Conferences No. 84], 1956, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conférence Nationale Souveraine
    - "Affaires Economiques, Financiers et Foncières", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Résolutions, Déclaration, et Appel", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Propos Scientifiques (Sciences Humaines - Développement), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Famille & Développement (revue trimestrielle Africane d'éducation et de coopération technique), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional material, 1981-2007; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1981-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)